Guide to the James Olinkiewicz Collection of Brooklyn Daily Eagle Postcards 1905-1907 PR 355
New-York Historical Society
James Olinkiewicz collection of Brooklyn Daily Eagle postcards
1905-1907
New-York Historical Society
Olinkiewicz, James
Brooklyn Daily Eagle (Firm)
PR 355
1 Linear feet (1 box)
A complete set of the 486 postcards depicting Brooklyn scenes issued by the Brooklyn Daily Eagle newspaper.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Olinkiewicz, August 2013.
Arrangement
The Brooklyn Daily Eagle issued its postcards in 81 weekly series of 6 cards per series, for a total of 486 cards. The cards are numbered consecutively from 1 to 486 and housed in a single box.
Historical Note
Beginning the week of 13 November 1905, and continuing through May 1907, the Brooklyn Daily Eagle, Brooklyn's leading newspaper, issued a series of remarkable postcards depicting virtually every notable structure and scene in the borough (see the Scope and Contents note for details). The cards were issued in weekly series of six, and offered gratis to paying readers of the paper who clipped daily coupons for each series and exchanged them at the Eagle's offices. Later, in response to demand, and as supplies allowed, the Eagle offered sets for sale. Today they frequently turn up individually in collections and online auctions, but complete sets of all 486 Brooklyn Eagle cards, such as this one assembled by James Olinkiewicz, are rare.
The best introduction to the cards is Richard L. Dutton's Brooklyn: The Brooklyn Daily Eagle Postcards, 1905-1907 (Arcadia Publishing, 2004).
Related Archival Materials
A number of the Brooklyn Daily Eagle postcards are duplicated in the New-York Historical Society Postcard Collection (PR-054), Subseries II.B, Boxes 56-58.
Scope and Contents
Although they emphasize developed neighborhoods like Brooklyn Heights, Fort Greene, Clinton Hill, Bedford-Stuyvesant, Park Slope, Prospect Park South, Flatbush, and Coney Island, the Brooklyn Eagle postcards present a dizzying range of subjects scattered throughout the borough. Full card captions are transcribed in the container list, but the images a researcher can expect to find include amusement parks, armories, art museums, athletic clubs, banks, beaches, bridges, cemeteries, charitable institutions, churches (Baptist, Congregationalist, Episcopal, Lutheran, Presbyterian, Reformed, Roman Catholic, Unitarian) and synagogues, colleges and universities, convents, courthouses, department stores, entertainment venues, factories, firehouses, historic houses, horse racing, hospitals, hotels, industrial districts, infrastructure, ironworks, jails, landmarks, learned institutions, libraries, markets, morgues, nursing homes, office buildings, orphanages, parks, police stations, political clubs, public schools, recreational areas, refineries, reformatories, residences, restaurants, roller-skating rinks, shipping, statues and monuments, streets, theaters, transportation, warehouses, waterfronts, and waterworks. A few of the cards depict people: school principals, mainly, and prominent clergymen, and, towards the end of the series, actors appearing in plays at the Montauk Theatre.
Note that the dates in the container list signify when the postcards were issued, NOT when the photographs were taken. In some cases the cards reproduce images that were made at least thirteen to fifteen years earlier than the 1905-1907 period. See, for instance, Souvenir of Our Public Schools (New York: E. J. Whitlock, 1892), the source of many of the images on the Eagle's school building postcards.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Postcards.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 1, 1905 November 13-18 (Box 1 of 1)
  Scope and Contents
  001 | Litchfield Mansion, Prospect Park.
  002 | Erasmus Hall High School. (Now [sic] Building.)
  003 | Entrance of the Museum of the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences. (Under Construction.)
  004 | The Williamsburgh Bridge, From Broadway, Brooklyn, to Delancey St., Manhattan.
  005 | Excavating for the New Long Island Railroad Station.
  006 | Old Academy of Music, Montague St. (Burned Nov. 30, 1903.)
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 2, 1905 November 20-25 (Box 1 of 1)
  007 | Museum of the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences, Eastern Parkway. (Under Construction.)
  008 | Soldiers' and Sailors' Memorial Arch, Main Entrance, Prospect Park.
  009 | View of Brooklyn Water Front, 1840.
  010 | Packer Collegiate Institute, Joralemon St., Near Clinton. Founded in 1844.
  011 | New Giant Twin-Screw S.S. Amerika of the Hamburg-American Line.
  012 | Croquet Club House, Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 3, 1905 November 27-December 2 (Box 1 of 1)
  013 | Entrance to Dreamland, Coney Island.
  014 | Public School No. 136, 4th Ave. and 40th St.
  015 | Site of Fulton Ferry, 1746.
  016 | Temple Israel, Cor. Bedford and Lafayette Aves.
  017 | A Play Near the Goal Line in the Boys' High School-Pratt Institute Game at Washington Park.
  018 | Bronze Statue of Abraham Lincoln, Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 4, 1905 December 4-9 (Box 1 of 1)
  019 | Christ Protestant Episcopal Church, Cor. Clinton and Harrison Streets.
  020 | Unique Japanese House in Prospect Park South.
  021 | Sheep on the Long Meadow, Prospect Park.
  022 | Brooklyn Savings Bank Building, Clinton and Pierrepont Streets.
  023 | Boys' High School, Marcy and Putnam Avenues.
  024 | Statue of John Howard Payne, in the Flower Garden, Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 5, 1905 December 11-16 (Box 1 of 1)
  025 | Beach in Front of Coney Island Park.
  026 | Simpson M.E. Church, Willoughby and Clermont Aves. Rev. Wm. J. Thompson, Pastor.
  027 | Public School No. 35, Lewis Ave. and Decatur St.
  028 | Steamers Loading Exports in the Atlantic Basin.
  029 | Old 13th Regiment Armory, Razed to Make Way for the L.I.R.R. Station.
  030 | Busy Thoroughfare at Broadway and Gates Ave.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 6, 1905 December 18-23 (Box 1 of 1)
  031 | Bronze Bust of Thomas Moore in Prospect Park.
  032 | Public Library corner Pacific St. and 4th Ave.
  033 | People's Trust Company Building, Montague Street, near Clinton.
  034 | Public School No. 137, Saratoga Avenue and Bainbridge Street.
  035 | Brooklyn in 1820 — From Guy's Painting, Now in the Possession of The Brooklyn Institute.
  036 | Church of Our Lady of Lourdes, Broadway and De Sales Place.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 7, 1905 December 25-30 (Box 1 of 1)
  037 | Manual Training High School, Seventh Ave. and Fourth St.
  038 | Select Residential Section, Ditmas Park.
  039 | Marcy Avenue Baptist Church, Corner Marcy and Putnam Avenues.
  040 | Recreation Pier at the Foot of North Second Street.
  041 | Brownsville Fire House.
  042 | Main Entrance Greenwood Cemetery.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 8, 1906 January 1-6 (Box 1 of 1)
  043 | Dime Savings Bank Building, cor. Court and Remsen Streets.
  044 | Gardens of the Convent of the Sisters of Mercy, cor. Classon and Willoughby Avenues.
  045 | South 3d Street Presbyterian Church, S. 3d St. and Driggs Ave.
  046 | Girls' High School, cor. Nostrand Ave. and Halsey St.
  047 | View Along the Shore Road.
  048 | The Terrace at the Flower Garden, Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 9, 1906 January 8-13 (Box 1 of 1)
  049 | Flatbush Branch, Public Library, on Linden Avenue.
  050 | Public School No. 12, Adelphi Street, Near Myrtle Avenue.
  051 | Shopping District, Belmont Avenue and Osborne Street, Brownsville.
  052 | Clinton Avenue Congregational Church, Clinton and Lafayette Avenues.
  053 | Prospect Hill Water Tower.
  054 | New Montauk Theatre.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 10, 1906 January 15-20 (Box 1 of 1)
  055 | Brooklyn Club, Clinton and Pierrepont Streets.
  056 | New Bear Cage in Prospect Park.
  057 | Throop Ave. Presbyterian Church, Throop Ave. Cor. Willoughby. L.R. Foote, Pastor for 30 Years.
  058 | Public School [No.] 132, Manhattan and Metropolitan Avenues.
  059 | Young Women's Christian Association Building, Schermerhorn Street and Flatbush Avenue.
  060 | Old Brooklyn Theater, Post Office and Police Station, 1873 — Present Site of Eagle Building.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 11, 1906 January 22-27 (Box 1 of 1)
  061 | Central Building, Brooklyn Bureau of Charities, Schermerhorn St., near Court.
  062 | P.S. No. 123, Irving Ave. Between Suydam St. and Willoughby Ave.
  063 | Church of the New Jerusalem (Swedenborgian), Monroe Place and Clark Street.
  064 | Fort Hamilton Park fronting The Narrows.
  065 | The Minnesota — One of the Finest Battleships in the Navy.
  066 | Bird's-Eye View Looking From Court Square Towards the Navy Yard.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 12, 1906 January 29-February 3 (Box 1 of 1)
  067 | German Evangelical Lutheran Zion Church, Henry St., which Recently Celebrated its Fiftieth Anniversary.
  068 | Midwood Club, Ocean Avenue, near Caton.
  069 | Public School No. 139, Avenue C and E. 13th Street.
  070 | Flatbush Ave. at Linden Ave., Eagle Flatbush Branch on the Left.
  071 | J.S.T. Stranahan Statue — Prospect Park.
  072 | Friends' Burying Ground — Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 13, 1906 February 5-10 (Box 1 of 1)
  073 | Fleet Street M.E. Church. Parsonage and Sunday-School Room.
  074 | Public School No. 5, Duffield and Johnson Streets.
  075 | Marine and Field Club House, Bath Beach.
  076 | Brooklyn Water Front, North of Wall Street Ferry.
  077 | Luna Park, Coney Island.
  078 | The Basin and Cob Dock, Navy Yard.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 14, 1906 February 12-17 (Box 1 of 1)
  079 | Polytechnic Institute, Livingston St., near Court.
  080 | First Dutch Reformed Church, Gravesend.
  081 | Pacific Baths, Foot of Pacific Street.
  082 | Cumberland Street Hospital.
  083 | Old Bull's Head Tavern on Flatbush Avenue in 1845.
  084 | Skating in Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 15, 1906 February 19-24 (Box 1 of 1)
  085 | Williamsburgh Trust Company Building, Williamsburg Bridge Plaza.
  086 | Public School No. 5, Academy Street near Grand Avenue, L.I. City.
  087 | Section of Fourth Avenue Showing Parked Section in Middle of Highway.
  088 | St. John's Lutheran Church, New Jersey Avenue, near Liberty Avenue.
  089 | "The Abbey" in 1835 — Fulton Avenue, near Junction of Hudson Avenue.
  090 | The "Caronia" of the Cunard Line, one of the Largest Ocean Liners in the World.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 16, 1906 February 26-March 3 (Box 1 of 1)
  091 | Riding and Driving Club's New Garage on Park Plaza.
  092 | Wallabout Market and United States Marine Hospital.
  093 | St. Luke's P.E. Church, Clinton Avenue; Rev. Henry C. Swentzel, Rector.
  094 | Erie Basin.
  095 | Public School No. 119, Avenue K and East Thirty-Eighth Street.
  096 | Brooklyn City Hall, from an Old Print.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 17, 1906 March 5-10 (Box 1 of 1)
  097 | View of Brooklyn, looking towards the Brooklyn Bridge — Holy Trinity Church in the Foreground.
  098 | St. Ann's P.E. Church, Clinton and Livingston Sts.
  099 | Brownsville State Bank.
  100 | Bader's Famous Road House — Ocean Parkway and King's Highway.
  101 | Sugar Refineries along Brooklyn's Water Front.
  102 | P.S. 112, 15th Avenue and 71st Street.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 18, 1906 March 12-17 (Box 1 of 1)
  103 | View up Fulton Street from Borough Hall.
  104 | Fulton St., between Lawrence and Bridge Sts., 1776. Octagon Church believed to be First Public School in Brooklyn.
  105 | Public School No. 127, Seventh Avenue and 79th Street.
  106 | Plymouth Church, Orange Street, near Hicks, (Congregational.) Rev. Newell Dwight Hillis, Pastor.
  107 | Flatbush Trust Company Building on Flatbush Avenue.
  108 | Greenpoint and Manhattan Avenues, Looking Toward Long Island City.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 19, 1906 March 19-24 (Box 1 of 1)
  109 | Public Library, Fourth Avenue and 51st Street.
  110 | Market Places on Moore Street.
  111 | Twenty-second Avenue, Show Street of Bensonhurst.
  112 | Sunset Park.
  113 | Public School No. 3, Hancock St., near Bedford Ave.
  114 | Puritan Cong. Church, Lafayette Ave., cor. Marcy.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 20, 1906 March 26-31 (Box 1 of 1)
  115 | Junction Fulton Street and DeKalb Avenue About 1850.
  116 | Public School No. 11, Washington Avenue near Greene.
  117 | Inspection of Forty-seventh Regiment by Gen. James McLeer.
  118 | Synagogue Beth Elohim, State Street, near Hoyt.
  119 | Federal Building, cor. Washington and Johnson Sts.
  120 | Hanover Club, Bedford Avenue and Rodney Street.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 21, 1906 April 2-7 (Box 1 of 1)
  121 | St. Augustine's R.C. Church, Sixth Avenue, Cor. Sterling Place.
  122 | Friends' School, on Schermerhorn Street Near Smith Street.
  123 | Fort Hamilton in Winter.
  124 | Brooklyn Daily Eagle Building, Corner Washington and Johnson Streets.
  125 | Junction Broadway and Myrtle Avenue.
  126 | Pretty Section of Manhattan Terrace.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 22, 1906 April 9-14 (Box 1 of 1)
  127 | Fort Greene Park.
  128 | Kings County Democratic Club, Schermerhorn Street, Near Smith.
  129 | Church of the Guardian Angel, Coney Island.
  130 | Commerical High School, Albany Ave., between Dean and Bergen Sts.
  131 | Garfield Building, Court and Remsen Streets.
  132 | Sheepshead Bay Police Precinct.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 23, 1906 April 16-21 (Box 1 of 1)
  133 | Bensonhurst Beach and Park.
  134 | Temple Bar Building, Court and Joralemon Streets.
  135 | Original East River Bridge, Winter of 1852.
  136 | Monument of Major-General Gouverneur Kemble Warren, Facing Prospect Park.
  137 | Tompkins Avenue Congregational Church, Tompkins Avenue, corner McDonough Street.
  138 | Public School No. 126, Meserole Avenue and Lorimer Street.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 24, 1906 April 23-28 (Box 1 of 1)
  139 | Andrews M.E. Church, Richmond Street near Etna.
  140 | Narrows from Fort Hamilton, 1852.
  141 | Public School No. 64, Belmont Avenue, between Berriman Street and Atkins Avenue.
  142 | Manhattan Avenue, Looking South from Greenpoint Avenue.
  143 | Jenkins Trust Company Building, Nostrand and Gates Avenues.
  144 | Inspecting Companies of Marines at the Brooklyn Navy Yard.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 25, 1906 April 30-May 5 (Box 1 of 1)
  145 | A Brownsville Street Scene — Looking up Belmont Avenue Toward Powell Street.
  146 | Church of the Redeemer, Fourth Avenue and Pacific Street.
  147 | Busy Dock Scene at the Bush Terminal.
  148 | Phoenix Building, Court Street near Montague.
  149 | Methodist Episcopal Hospital, Sixth St., from Seventh to Eighth Ave.
  150 | Public School No. 1, Concord and Adams Streets.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 26, 1906 May 7-12 (Box 1 of 1)
  151 | Public School No. 15, State Street and Third Avenue.
  152 | Old Brooklyn Tabernacle.
  153 | Real Estate Exchange Building, 197 Montague Street.
  154 | General View of Manhattan Beach, as seen from Brighton.
  155 | Fine Residential Section, Arlington Avenue, East New York.
  156 | Flatbush Water-Works.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 27, 1906 May 14-19 (Box 1 of 1)
  157 | Public School 138, Prospect Place, near Nostrand Avenue.
  158 | St. Agnes' Church, Sackett and Hoyt Streets.
  159 | Corner of Central Wood Yard, on Pacific Street.
  160 | Clarendon Hotel, Johnson and Washington Sts.
  161 | The Kearsage, one of the finest Battleships of the U.S. Navy.
  162 | Entrance to Rose Garden, Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 28, 1906 May 21-26 (Box 1 of 1)
  163 | Church of St. Stanislaus Kotska, Driggs Avenue and Humboldt Street.
  164 | Public School 91, East New York and Albany Avenues.
  165 | Brooklyn Rapid Transit Terminal, 65th Street.
  166 | University Club, on South Elliott Place.
  167 | Alexander Hamilton Bronze Statue, Hamilton Club, Remsen and Clinton Streets.
  168 | Wireless Station at Sea Gate.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 29, 1906 May 28-June 2 (Box 1 of 1)
  169 | Public School 142, Henry and Rapelye Streets.
  170 | Central Presbyterian Church, Jefferson and Marcy Avenues.
  171 | Lake in Institute Park.
  172 | U.S. Training Brig for the Training of Landsmen and Apprentices in the Art of Seamanship.
  173 | County Jail, Raymond Street.
  174 | Tropical Pond — Victoria Regia [sic] — Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 30, 1906 June 4-9 (Box 1 of 1)
  175 | View of the Heights from the Eagle Tower.
  176 | Toll House, Flatbush, 1877.
  177 | Tabernacle Baptist Church, Clinton St. and Third Pl., Rev. Erwin Dennett, Pastor.
  178 | United States Battleship Idaho Recently Launched.
  179 | Select Residential Section, Eighth Avenue and Carroll Street, Looking East.
  180 | Gates Avenue Looking Towards Broadway.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 31, 1906 June 11-16 (Box 1 of 1)
  181 | Bascule Bridge Over Newtown Creek.
  182 | Greenpoint Library.
  183 | Environs of Williamsburg Bridge Plaza.
  184 | Eastern Parkway From Prospect Park to Highland Park.
  185 | Model School, Brooklyn Training School for Teachers.
  186 | St. James' Convent, Johnson and Pearl Streets.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 32, 1906 June 18-23 (Box 1 of 1)
  187 | The Jewish Hospital, Classon and St. Marks Avenues.
  188 | Birdseye View Atlantic Dock.
  189 | Gowanus Canal Below Fifteenth Street.
  190 | Alhambra Apartment House, Nostrand Avenue.
  191 | Looking Toward Heyward St. and Bedford Ave. from Broadway and Marcy Ave.
  192 | Public School No. 110, Monitor Street, cor. Driggs Avenue.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 33, 1906 June 25-30 (Box 1 of 1)
  193 | Brooklyn College of Pharmacy Building.
  194 | Public School 146, 18th St., near 6th Ave.
  195 | Holy Rosary Church, Chauncey St. and Reid Ave.
  196 | Ocean Flyer "Baltic" of the White Star Line.
  197 | Owl's Head, on the Shore Road.
  198 | Williamsburgh Trust Co. Building, on Fulton St.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 34, 1906 July 2-7 (Box 1 of 1)
  199 | Norwegian Hospital, on 4th Avenue.
  200 | Borough Hall.
  201 | Brighton Beach Hotel.
  202 | Vessels at Foot of 56th Street ready for the Summer Season.
  203 | Brooklyn Heights and New York Harbor.
  204 | Mechanics Bank Building, Court and Montague Sts.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 35, 1906 July 9-14 (Box 1 of 1)
  205 | Bedford Corners, 1777.
  206 | Show House, Prospect Park.
  207 | Thomas Jefferson Building, Court Square.
  208 | Gravesend Town Hall.
  209 | Flatbush Firemen's House.
  210 | People's Bank, Broadway and Greene Avenue.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 36, 1906 July 16-21 (Box 1 of 1)
  211 | Henry Ward Beecher Statue, Facing Borough Hall.
  212 | Home of the Aged, on Chauncey Street.
  213 | The Touraine Apartment House, Clinton St.
  214 | The Rose Garden in Prospect Park.
  215 | Battleship "New Jersey," U.S. Navy.
  216 | Proposed Big Freight Yard for South Brooklyn.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 37, 1906 July 23-28 (Box 1 of 1)
  217 | The "Kansas" Taking her Initial Dip in the Waters of the Delaware.
  218 | Franklin Trust Company Building, Clinton and Montague Streets.
  219 | Junction of Court, Fulton and Washington Streets.
  220 | Looking South from Pierrepont Street — 1836.
  221 | Prospect Park Parade Grounds.
  222 | The Old Hicks Residence on Hicks Street, One of the Landmarks on the Heights.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 38, 1906 July 30-August 4 (Box 1 of 1)
  223 | Bay Ridge Parkway and Ocean Driveway, Looking from Fourth Ave. at Sixty-Sixth St.
  224 | Free Floating Baths, Foot of Conover Street.
  225 | A Coney Island Attraction.
  226 | Clinton Avenue, Brooklyn's Show Street.
  227 | Home of the Teachers' Club, 293 Henry Street.
  228 | Greenpoint Branch of Corn Exchange Bank, Franklin and Greenpoint Aves.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 39, 1906 August 6-11 (Box 1 of 1)
  229 | Sea Wall, South of Concourse, Coney Island.
  230 | Spanish Guns and Commandant's Residence, Navy Yard.
  231 | Crescent Club Boat House, on the Shore Road.
  232 | Brooklyn Hospital.
  233 | Germania Savings Bank Building, on Fulton Street.
  234 | Brooklyn Atheneum Building, Atlantic Avenue and Clinton Street.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 40, 1906 August 13-18 (Box 1 of 1)
  235 | Kaiser Wilhelm der Grosse.
  236 | Avenue D and Dorchester Road, Ditmas Park.
  237 | Seaside Home, Coney Island.
  238 | Nassau Trust Company Building, Fulton Street.
  239 | Vale of Cashmere, Prospect Park.
  240 | Coney Island Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 41, 1906 August 20-25 (Box 1 of 1)
  241 | Entrance to Evergreen Cemetery.
  242 | New Swedish Hospital, Sterling Place and Rogers Avenue.
  243 | National City Bank Building, Fulton Street and Red Hook Lane.
  244 | Section of Bay Ridge Parkway at 65th St., East of Third Ave.
  245 | Parkway Driving Club House.
  246 | Rustic Arch Near Farm House, Prospect Park.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 42, 1906 August 27-September 1 (Box 1 of 1)
  247 | Municipal Building.
  248 | The Lower East River, Showing Water Front from South Ferry to Gowanus Bay.
  249 | SS. "Republic," White Star Line.
  250 | Busy Corner, Broadway and Flushing Avenue.
  251 | Nurses Home, Kingston Avenue Hospital.
  252 | Prospect Park, Battle Pass — 1776.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 43, 1906 September 3-8 (Box 1 of 1)
  253 | South Brooklyn Savings Bank, Atlantic Avenue, corner Clinton Street.
  254 | Surf Avenue, Coney Island.
  255 | Beautiful Ditmas Park.
  256 | U.S. Ambulance Ship "Solace."
  257 | Site of Hooley's Opera House, cor. Court and Remsen Sts. Present Site of Dime Savings Bank.
  258 | Grant's Statue, Bedford Avenue and Bergen Street.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 44, 1906 September 10-15 (Box 1 of 1)
  259 | Site of Long Island Club — 1868.
  260 | Broadway Bank Building.
  261 | House of the Good Shepherd.
  262 | Ravenswood Boat Club House.
  263 | An Attractive Bit of Prospect Park South.
  264 | SS. "Moltke" — Hamburg American Line.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 45, 1906 September 17-22 (Box 1 of 1)
  265 | Church of Our Saviour, Unitarian, Monroe Place and Pierrepont Street.
  266 | Public School No. 68, on Bushwick Avenue.
  267 | Manufacturers' National Bank, Broadway and Berry Street.
  268 | Fountain — Vale of Cashmere[,] Prospect Park.
  269 | A Favorite Attraction at Coney Island.
  270 | The "Carmania," of the Cunard Line, Largest Turbine Steamship Afloat.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 46, 1906 September 24-29 (Box 1 of 1)
  271 | Fulton Street Before "L" Road or Trolleys.
  272 | "Taking a Hurdle," Prospect Park.
  273 | Public School No. 26, Gates Avenue near Patchen.
  274 | Beautiful Beverley Road, Flatbush.
  275 | St. Joseph's R.C. Church, Vanderbilt Avenue and Pacific Street.
  276 | Brooklyn Bank, Fulton and Clinton Streets.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 47, 1906 October 1-6 (Box 1 of 1)
  277 | American Liner "New York."
  278 | Panoramic View of Brooklyn, Showing Greenpoint, Brooklyn Bridge, Navy Yard, Ft. Greene Park and the Heights.
  279 | Brevoort Savings Bank, Nostrand Avenue and Macon Street.
  280 | The Dairy — Prospect Park.
  281 | Parish House — Church of St. Mark, Eastern Parkway and Brooklyn Avenue.
  282 | Public School No. 37, S. Fourth Street near Berry.
- Brooklyn Eagle Postcard Series 48, 1906 October 8-13 (Box 1 of 1)
  283 | The East River. Showing Brooklyn and Williamsburgh [sic] Bridges.
  284 | Terrace Bridge and Maryland Monument, Prospect Park.
  285 | Sanitarium for Hebrew Children, Rockaway Park.
  286 | "Amerika," Hamburg American Line.
  287 | Public School No. 147, Bushwick Avenue and Seigel Street, Principal Charles D. Raine, Ph.D.